Pieter Montoulieu

README

Hey there, my name is Pieter Montoulieu and I'm a XR developer and full-stack React engineer currently building with Next.js and Unity.

I've been developing for the web for 20 years now and have always loved building with the latest and best technologies that are available.

Over the past 5 years, I have spent a lot of time working on frontends for health, financial, and real estate clients like Flexpool, Remax, Davita, and WOW Telecom. While these were all great experiences that allowed me to grow as a developer, I am currently looking to work for companies with more of an artistic spirit and culture to the way they operate.

XR SKILLS

Unity

- C# (8+ years)
- SteamVR/OVR/XR Interaction/HurricaneVR
- Shader Graph
- URP/HDRP
- Probuilder
- Audio Mixer
- Physics (Rigidbodies, Joints, etc)
- UT
- SCM / Collab

3D / Graphics

- Blender
- Maya
- Photoshop
- Figma

Audio / Video

- Sound Effect Design
- Chiptune / Retro Video Game Music
- Orchestral Composition
- Logic / Ableton 10
- Davinci Resolve / Final Cut Pro

WEBDEV SKILLS

React / React Native

- Next.js
- Gatsby
- Expo
- State Management (Redux, MobX, Flux, Zustand, xState, Context)
- Styled Components

Javascript

- ES9
- Node / Express
- Serverless and LAMBDA functions
- Webpack / PostCSS

PHP

- Laravel
- Wordpress
- Apache/Nginx

UI

- Tailwind, Bootstrap, Material UI, Foundation
- Storybook

DB

- GraphQL
- MySQL / PostgreSQL

Deployment

- Git and version control
- Netlify, Vercel
- DigitalOcean
- AWS, Azure

EXPERIENCE

Montoulieu Corp, Denver - CEO, Lead Engineer

NOV 2019 - PRESENT

Montoulieu Corp is the game and web development company that I started. We've worked with local clients like Colorado Film School and have built out XR concepts and prototypes over the last year.

Spire Digital, Denver - Full Stack Engineer

DEC 2018 - PRESENT

Spire Digital is an agency with awesome leadership and work culture, which has led to some great client relationships.

During my time here I've been able to build a customer facing React SPA for WOW Internet Communications and an internal SPA for RE/MAX, which is used nationally by their agents to automate video and image ads for all their housing listings.

Graphik Creative, Denver - Full Stack Engineer

NOV 2015 - OCT 2018

Graphik was a great company to work with, I got to lead a dev team on internal React and Laravel applications for DaVita, Vail Resorts and other local Colorado companies as well as hone my eye for design and typography.

Orange Collar Media, Location — Frontend Developer

FEB 2014 - OCT 2015

My time at Orange Collar Media was a great learning experience for working with multiple clients and learning more PHP and Magento. During my time there I built several storefronts for national and local Colorado businesses.

EDUCATION

Barron Collier High School, Naples, FL

May 2003 - May 2007, Naples, FL